Punith Ch

Software Developer



About Me

Full-Stack developer with over eight years of experience in implementing best practices like test-driven development and introducing DevOps techniques such as continuous deployment, following good principles like SOLID and DRY.

Contacts

- 278 Saddlebrook Circle, NE Calgary, AB, T3J 0K2
- +1 (825) 561 1617
- info@punith.ca
- https://punith.alphatric.com/

Hobbies







Education

Postgraduate in Information Technology 2014-2015 Lambton College

Bachelor's in technology 2009-2013 SRM University

Experience

Full-Stack Developer

ATB Financial, July 2021 – Present & May 2018 - Dec 2018

Java, Spring Boot, NodeJS, React, Redux, Ant Design

- Developed backend and frontend solutions for ATB internal applications.
- Exposed REST and GRAPHQL based Api's using NESTJS.
- Developed process Api's to integrate Salesforce and SAP CRM with error handling.
- Services are developed using event driven architecture
- Developed Front end applications using React in TDD.
- Integrated 3rd party credit card services into internal applications.
- Used Spring boot to develop enterprise Api's.
- Used cloud build and cloud run with docker images to deploy applications.
- Developed applications on GCP.
- Used pytest for Api automation tests
- Used React testing library with Jest for unit tests and Playwright (Migrating from Selenium) for automation testing.

Full-Stack Developer

Motorola Solutions, May 2020 - July 2021

NodeJS, HapiJS, React, Redux, Jest, Azure Dev-ops, gRPC, Docker

- Designed and Developed Api's using NodeJS with HapiJS framework.
- Built in-house media player for web client using react.
- Worked with NodeJS streams to facilitate video streaming, notifications, and alarms.
- Configured Api's to be available in different transports like REST, Realtime, IoT, and WebRTC.
- Configured Feeds and pipelines for Azure Dev-ops.
- Refactored existing test suites in Tape framework to Jest tests
- Used Gulp as a build tool.
- Provided support for developer forum, which is used by integrators.
- Identifying ways to improve API documentation for internal and external customers.
- Implemented rate limiting for end points
- Used Open API (Swagger) for documentation.
- Used Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket with Bamboo (transitioned to Azure-Dev-ops)



Languages

- Typescript
- Python
- Javascript
- GraphQL
- HTML /CSS
- SQL
- Java



Frameworks

- Express
- NestJS
- HapiJS
- React / Redux
- Spring Boot



Databases

- PostgreSQL
- Firestore
- Prisma and TypeORM
- Hibernate



Aws & GCP

- Lambda Functions
- Step Functions
- Event Bridge
- SQS
- Cloud Build
- Cloud Run



Tools

- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Postman
- Swagger

Full-Stack Developer

VOG App Developers, Jan 2019 - May 2020

C#, .NET Core, React, Redux, AWS, NodeJS, Docker, PostgreSQL

- Developed Backend REST Api's using .Net core for Mobile applications and Admin Panels using React
- Used AWS services like AWS Lambda, Step Functions, Amplify, RDS and ECS for developing and deploying applications
- Worked with graphic designers and converted designs to visual elements.
- Develop, maintain, and support admin panels that are developed using react-redux
- Collaborated with the team to identify the MVP's key requirements and assemble the requirements doc

Software Developer

Shaw Communications, Jan 2017-May 2018

NodeJS, React, Redux, Spring Boot

- Developed JSON RESTful API Services for Internal workflow management application including OAuth, user profiles, messages
- Used Ajax, JSON with jQuery for request data and response processing.
- Developed web client with mobile and Tab screen support using ReactJS, Redux.
- Discussed, analyzed, and strategized product design with product managers, UX team and business managers.
- Used Jest and Enzyme for unit testing

Software Engineer

SparxIT - Contractor, Aug 2015 – Jan 2017

Spring MVC, SPRING JPA, Hibernate, Java, NodeJS

- Developed a single-page web application Customer Portal for customers of TCR
- The application allows users to register, login, reset password and review outstanding balance.
- Implemented session timeouts, browser cookie management, and parts of application error handling.
- Integrated with stripe, and interac api's for payments
- Used Ajax, JSON with jQuery for request data and response processing.
- Used SQL migrations and Hibernate ORM to access MYSQL databases

Application Support Analyst

Accenture, May 2013 – Aug 2014

SPRING MVC, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery

- Supported enterprise application in production by fixing bugs and providing technical support for different teams.
- Build MVC applications using .net MVC and Razor pages
- Used Bootstrap UI library